# Joshua Haughton

## **FULLSTACK DEVELOPER**

□(+1) 416-998-3238 | Sitsjoshuahauqhton@qmail.com | Portfolio: # joshuahauqhton.github.io | @ JoshuaHauqhton | 🛅 joshua-hauqhton-5ba15a22b

## Tech Stack\_

HTML5 · CSS3 · JavaScript ES6+ · Typescript · React.js · Next.js · Jest · Mocha + Chai · Node.js · Express.js · MongoDB · PostgreSQL · GraphQL · Firebase

## **Summary**

A highly motivated full-stack developer with a passion for designing apps that provide an exceptional user experience. Confident in using frontend libraries and frameworks such as React and Next.js, with experience utilizing back-end technologies and eagerness to acquire new skills. An enthusiastic collaborator with the ability to understand team needs and develop ideas to meet their objectives.

## **Experience**

#### **Moonbeam Trading Company**

Remote

WEB DEVELOPMENT INTERN (REACT, NEXT.JS)

Mar. 2022

- · Collaborated with others to develop a functional and responsive Next.js site from scratch for a small business.
- · Learned and applied Server-Side rendering knowledge to optimize SEO, speed up load times, and enhance user experience.
- · Led group discussions about other features to implement after completing work before deadlines

#### **STEER.us** (Talent Development Agency)

Remote

WEB DEVELOPMENT INTERN (REACT, WORDPRESS)

Mar. 2022

- Performed bug fixes and React performance optimizations for multiple pages on the site.
- Updated CSS to provide a cleaner layout for users.

#### **Freelance Digital Marketer**

Remote

DIGITAL MARKETING SPECIALIST

Jan. 2021 - Mar. 2022

- Created and managed Facebook Ads and Email Marketing campaigns for small-mid sized E-Commerce businesses.
- Researched customer psychology and the best ways to target customer desires/pain points for enhancing user experience.

SportingLife (Retail)

Ottawa, ON
Dec. 2020 - Dec. 2021

FOOTWEAR DEPT SPECIALIST

- Positively greeted and communicated with customers and coworkers.
- Picked out specific shoes and boots best suited to each customer for their individual needs.

# **Projects**

#### **E-Commerce Website - Vinyl Fresh**

REACT.JS, REDUX, TYPESCRIPT, FIREBASE · DEMO · GITHUB

Dec. 2021 - Apr. 2022

• A dynamic E-commerce app where users can browse and order vinyl records based on popular album covers.

#### Movie Finder/Saver - Watchlist

REACT.JS, NODE.JS, EXPRESS.JS, MONGODB, TMDBAPI · DEMO · GITHUB

Dec. 2021 - Mar. 2022

• A media searching app, allowing users to find and save movies and tv shows to their watchlist, as well as rate them and check them off their list.

### Crypto Tracker

REACT.JS, NEXT.JS, REDUX, COINGECKO API, FIREBASE · DEMO · GITHUB

Apr. 2022 - May. 2022

• A Next. is app where users can find detailed information and chart data on their favourite Cryptocurrencies.

#### LinkedIn Remake

REACT.JS, REDUX, TYPESCRIPT, FIREBASE · DEMO · GITHUB

Mar. 2022 - Apr. 2022

A LinkedIn remake built to learn more about Redux and Typescript. Users can create an account, make posts, and view posts other users make
in real-time.

# **Education**

Web Development Diploma Oct. 2021 - Jan. 2022

• An Intensive 12-week Bootcamp which gave me a deep understanding of front-end/back-end languages, frameworks and programming concepts through many solo and collaborative projects.

Carleton University Ottawa, ON

B.A. IN PSYCHOLOGY (HALF-COMPLETE)

Sep. 2019 - Sep. 2021

• Completed 2 years towards degree; learned the customer psychology skills necessary to fully transition into digital marketing.